SeeDance 2.5 just released, [music] and
with it comes a lot of exciting new
updates. Over the last week, we've been
testing it and pushing it to
cinema-grade realism.
>> [music]
>> And in today's video, I'm going to teach
you how you can go from idea to final
execution at the highest standard,
[music]
so that you can charge the highest rates
in the industry for AI commercials or
short films. [music]
My name's Roe Keeth, and it's our
mission to create 100,000 new jobs for
creatives in the AI space. [music] So,
in today's video, we're going to also
teach you all of the new updates that
have come from SeeDance 2.5, as well as
teaching you where is the most
cost-effective [music] place that you
can use it right now. So, without
further ado, I want to show you a
project that we've worked on, which has
gone super viral on social media, and
this is that project that we made with
SeeDance 2.5.
>> Apparently, you can now generate
30-second long videos with SeeDance 2.5.
30 seconds is a long time, right?
[\h__\h]
>> How many images can you use as a
reference?
>> 50.
>> What?
>> You playing with me?
>> 50.
You now have full control over every
generation, every character.
>> [\h__\h] I shouldn't be here.
>> Okay, so that was super cool. Now, no,
that wasn't 1 30-second long generation.
We actually kind of separated it scene
by scene. So, we went, okay, so let's
say we had this scene right here, for
example, we would go and we'd find like
and design our own location for this.
We'd design all the characters that we
wanted in it. We'd design all the
objects that we wanted in it. And then
we would create that short sequence, and
then we would build and stitch it all
together in our editing software of
choice. Now, that's not to say that you
can't do one single 30-second long
generation and get an incredible output.
I'm about to show you that very, very
shortly. But, let's discuss all of the
new updates that have come to SeeDance
2.5. So, the first one is, as you
learned from this video, is that you can
now generate videos that are 30 seconds
long. You can one-shot prompts, which is
incredible. You can also upload 50 image
references in the prompt bar now. Not
only image references, but video
references, audio references. So, if you
want to have a certain specific voice
that stays consistent throughout your
generations, you can upload that. You
can upload 50 locations, 50 images of
certain products that you want to show
up in the video. You have a lot more
flexibility and control with this new
model. But, with more control, more
flexibility, and more time, all of that
equals more compute for these companies,
which means more cost for the end user.
So, let's talk about costs. SeeDance 2.5
right now is very, very expensive. To
generate a 30-second long video can cost
you anywhere between $40 to $60 right
now, which is criminal. And we've spent
thousands of dollars over the last week
making three different projects for
three different clients, and it has been
a very expensive process. However, I'm
going to teach you right now where you
can get unlimited SeeDance 2.5 for the
next 33 days, so you can play, test
around with it, and you can get that
right now on Higgsfield. So, we've left
a link in the top link in the
description, so you can go and get that
straight away if you're interested. And
thank you, Higgsfield, for sponsoring
today's video and giving everyone access
to unlimited, so we can play to our
heart's content. So, without further
ado, I'm going to show you what it looks
like to create a video that is
30-seconds long. So, here is that video,
and then I'm going to walk through the
process of how we made it all the way
from idea to execution, so you can
replicate the same process for your
brand or business.
>> Do you mind doing my back?
>> Not a chance, mate.
>> Come on, it'll only take
>> I'll do it for you, baby.
>> [\h__\h]
Fancy doing both of us?
>> Protects your skin.
Not your dignity.
>> I love that. This is honestly one of my
favorite videos that we've ever had the
chance to make. It just felt so fun, so
fresh to create, and the design for all
of this was such a laugh. So, I'm going
to walk you through how we came up with
the idea, how we structure the ideas,
because I think this is where the the
biggest part where everyone kind of
fails and crumbles is in this early
ideation phase. It's in that foundation
period before you start your project.
You need to have strong foundations so
that you can build on top of it. If you
don't have those, it's going to crumble,
your project will crumble, and it won't
end up looking exactly how you want. So,
here is what we do. So, I will go to
something like a simple as a Google Doc,
and I will say, "Okay, for this idea, I
came up with the core message." The core
message in this video was that we're
promoting a sun cream brand. Now, in
that, we then wrote out a list of things
that could be funny about that. So, we
were like, "Okay, uh you know, put
rubbing sun cream into your mate's back.
Uh maybe that would make some guys
uncomfortable. Let's do something around
that, and then let's have a character in
there who is really up for putting sun
cream on someone else's back. Uh what
could we design that character? What
could they look like?" So, we came up
with this really fun concept. Once we
had like a little like group discussion
with our team about ideation, and we had
this rough idea, it was then time to
start blocking the idea into real acting
performance. And this is key. This is
where most people will mess up. So, the
acting performance here, you can see.
For example, we'll start with me
describing the camera shot that we want
to open the scene. So, we'll say like a
medium shot, or a close-up shot, or a
wide shot, establishing shot. And we'll
we'll kind of write out that camera at
the start so we can picture it in our
head. Then, it will we'll kind of just
dictate it as though I'm a director,
right? And I'll say, "It starts with my
friend taking a sip of beer, me applying
sunscreen onto my arms." So, we're
describing the actions that we want. We
can hear the beach ambience, some
seagulls, some general conversation
ambience, the beach bar behind us. So,
really close your eyes when you have
these ideas and start imagining in your
head taking yourself into that
environment. What would you hear? What
would you see? Start picturing that
acting performance from your characters
in that specific environment and
location. So then, this is where the
acting performance comes in. It cuts to
a side shot of me with my friend blurred
in the background. My friend is blurred
here, you can see that the focus is on
me. So, we're picturing that camera shot
where you've got the focus on me and we
kind of got this shallow depth of field
and we've got my friend blurred in the
background. I'm looking down and I ask
my friend, "Do you mind doing my back
for me?" I turn my body slightly and I
point towards my back over my shoulder.
So, you see that we're describing I'm
picturing in my head as I'm talking,
"How would I say that if I was actually
doing it in real life?" Like, "Do you
mind doing my back for me?" It's
something like that and you have to
describe all these actions for best
results out of Seedance 2.5. So, let's
dive in a little further here. So, for
example here, when I got this really
great acting performance that you can
see right here from this character here,
which was super realistic, I
specifically asked for this. I said, "Um
he spits out his beer um that's in his
mouth and he laughs obnoxiously, okay?"
So, we need to use key describing words.
So, he laughs obnoxiously for half a
second. So, we're being very specific
with timing cuz if you just said he
laughs obnoxiously, he might laugh for
like 2 seconds and we don't want that.
We want very like good pacing of the
video. We want it to, you know, continue
to be enjoyable and we want like cuts.
We want it to be, you know, highly
engaging. So, he also has an Australian
accent. He says, "Fuck off, I'm not
doing that." And then it cuts to a
medium shot where we can see both of us
looking at each other and there are
people moving in the beach bar behind
us. This is key. We want to add moving
elements into the background of the
scene. We want to make sure that it
feels realistic. You've got that
realistic, you know, it's not just like
two people sat there and it's like
you're in a ghost town. We need to add
in these details, otherwise Seedance
won't do it. So, you've got to picture
as though you're on set, you're in that
location and you're filming it real,
okay? Take yourself into that
environment. So, I look disappointed
with my friend and I plead. You know,
it's using these key descriptive words.
So, saying that I'm pleading by saying,
"Come on. It'll only take" then I get
interrupted from a voice in the distance
and we hear a lady shout from behind us,
okay? So, you're like you're describing
it. The key part is that you really need
to be descriptive. And my script for a
30-second long project looks something
like this, about a page and a half of
writing, okay? What I would do is I
would then copy all of this and I would
go into Claude and I would say, um, "I
have an idea for a video, uh, using
Seedance 2.5. So, make the video 30
seconds. I want to give you, I've got
like the idea mapped out here. I'm going
to give you the script. I want you to
then write it and put it all into a
prompt that is 30 seconds long, okay?
So, we'll paste that in here and then
I'll also paste in my script. So, now
we've got the entire script in here and
we've also got my instructions. Now,
what's also really important is that we
give Claude all of the context of what
the environments look like, the
character sheets, the product sheets.
So, let me show you what that looked
like for us right now. So, first thing
we designed is our character sheets and
this is what a typical character sheet
looks like. You've got your front, side,
back, front close-up, top down view,
height of the character and then we've
got all of the details in here. We've
got, you know, the tattoos, the skin
textures, the eye colors, the color
palette of this character. Now, he was
good, but he didn't he didn't it wasn't
right for me. It didn't feel right. So,
what I then did was I tried him with a
hat. Still didn't feel right. Then I
tried him with a kind of surfy beach
blondie hair, and I eventually got to a
character that I was happy with. Now,
here is an extra bonus tip for you. If
you are going to create a character
sheet, I'll leave a prompt right here
that you can go ahead and copy to create
your own character sheet, and you want
to upload a reference image of your
character, a single reference photo, and
then you want to use GPT-2 as your image
model. GPT-2 creates some of the most
realistic characters with very good skin
texture and detail. Nanobanana Pro gives
you that plasticky skin texture look, so
we don't want to do that. And you can
design all of your character sheets
inside of Higgsfield. They've got all of
the top image models, so you can do all
of that right here inside of Higgsfield.
So, once you've uploaded the reference
image of your character, and you've got
this prompt in here, it will give you a
character sheet like this that you can
now use inside of Seedance. Now, we
replicated this process for all of the
characters that we wanted to use inside
of this scene. So, we went and designed
these characters, and we went and found
references of similar characters that we
like the look of, and you can use tools
like Pinterest to go and find the design
of certain characters that you like, and
then go and restyle them in your own
way. We obviously don't want to take
anything because you don't own the
copyright to that. So, you've got to go
and remake your own, give it your own
creative twist, your own creative spin
on it, so that you can have the
character that you like. But, designing
the characters and the locations is
essential. So, here is my character
sheet, for example. We then kind of took
a reference image of my face, and we
designed this character sheet here.
We've got my height, we've got all the
details. We've even got the details of
the hat in here, and the shark print on
the shorts. And you can see this was our
original image that we created, which
was the original idea behind this lady.
And we took this image as a reference,
which we created with AI, and then we
used that to create the character sheet
and design the clothing that she was
going to wear and everything all in our
text prompt. So, now we have our
character sheets locked in. It's now
time for one of the most important
parts, which is the location reference.
Now, why is the location reference so
important? It's because it locks in the
color grade throughout the rest of your
project. And you want to make sure
you've got a really nice color grade for
your location. You don't just want to
take a normal, overcast, boring, plain
color graded image. You want to find
something that looks good, that gives
you the vibe. So, we created this image
here. But how do we get to a nice
location with a good color grade? Well,
it all comes from fantastic references.
So, you can use platforms any image
platform like Pinterest, Cosmos, loads
of different image platforms out there
where you can find really cinematic
frames. Okay? So, this is an example.
Beautiful color grading. You know, you
might find a shot like this or like this
for example, like this video here uh
looks absolutely beautiful. You know,
you might find a shot that you just
absolutely love the color grading of and
you want to design your location inside
that environment. So, let's say I love
the color grading on this one right
here. What you can do is you can
download that image and we can upload
that inside of Hexfield in here
uh right in here and we can say I like
to design a nice sandy beach in the same
environment with the same color grade,
but I'd like there to be a wooden beach
hut with a straw roof and a little sign
that says love shack and a surfboard
leaning up against a palm tree and
there's got to be nice like deck chairs
where people can sit on, but let's have
no people in the scene, okay? So, now we
can go ahead and generate that. You can
either use Nano Banana Pro or you can
test out some of the other image models
like SeaDream, which is also a super
realistic one. Or we could even try
Let's try GPT-2 as well. So, we're going
to run a couple of generations in here,
and then we're going to see which gives
us the best result. So, while that's
loading, what we can do is we can upload
all of the image references that we have
that we're going to use inside of this
prompt. So, for example, let's say we
wanted to use this reference here, we
can go ahead and upload that as well as
all the characters that we're going to
use inside of our video. So, let's go
ahead and upload all three of our
characters in here. So, we've got
myself, my friend, and also the lady
behind the bar. Now, we can go ahead and
go back and have a look at our
locations. So, now we've got some
beautiful color-graded shots in here.
Some of them are looking a little AI,
but they're not too bad. So, you can go
ahead and do some refinement, I'd say.
NanoBanana Pro has given us some pretty
good ones.
Uh Like this is really, really nice. I
actually quite like this. Could do with
maybe like a bit more of a bar kind of
scene where there's, you know, some
alcohol and like a bit more life in it.
This feels pretty lifeless, but the
color grade is there, right? So, you can
go ahead and refine this prompt until
you get like a nice bar that you're
happy with, for example. So, let's do
that together. So, let's say we wanted
to reuse our prompt in here with
NanoBanana Pro. We can also add in Add
in a some alcohol and a shelf of alcohol
in the the love shack. We also would
like a little bit more life and soul, so
maybe add some like fairy lights, some
party lights, a lot more seating. We
need more deck chairs, maybe like more
like a couple of tables and chairs for
people to sit at. We want more of like a
community vibe, okay? So, we can add
that into our prompt in here, and then
we can go ahead and generate a couple
variations of those. So, those are going
to start loading in. And then, once
you've got your location reference, so
let's say for example, we just took the
one that we just made, you can upload
your location that you've got with the
color grading that you're happy with
locked in. With all of this here, now
you can go ahead and run it. And I know
we haven't got our new location designed
yet, but let's just say we ran this as a
test subject. Now, Claude is going to go
through, read through our original
script, our idea, and it's also going to
listen to our instructions that we want
to create a 30-second prompt. Now, here
is where the key thing kicks in, is that
I have a C Dance skill that creates a
prompt with perfect structure. It time
codes everything. And not only that, it
also uses really nice camera presets, so
that all of our generations come out
looking like a professional grade
camera. And it also uses the same camera
lens, same camera body, same everything,
same focal length. A lot of the shots
remain the same. So, between all of the
cuts of our scenes, every shot feels
like it's been shot on the same camera.
We have the same color grading, same
characters, same details, same camera
lens, body, everything remains
consistent. And that is so important
when you're creating high-quality grade
AI work. So, if you want access to our
own custom C Dance skill, then you can
get that in the description as well. So,
here is our new environment. I would say
the text up here looks pretty AI, but
we're we're getting closer with the
decking and the seating, and this is
starting to look a little bit more
realistic. It's all about creating that
initial vibe that you want. And this was
the vibe that we chose for our actual
project, but this one here also looks
pretty good. I would probably take this
into Photoshop and remove this and add
my own text in that doesn't feel so like
AI and perfect, but overall, I'd
actually just remove this sign, and it
would look really, really nice. I
wouldn't remove this sign inside of Nano
Banana, because each time you regenerate
the image it's just going to reduce that
quality and suck all that quality away.
But this is pretty good. So you could
download that and go back into Claude.
Now you can see in here what we've got
here is my perfect prompt structure. So
you can see we've got the global look
and this is our prompt that we're
designing for SeaDance 2.5, okay? Now
you can see at the start of all my
prompts I have the camera, right? I've
got the lens, I've got
all of the key terminology in here, the
depth of field, the halation of the
lighting. I've got all of these like
fine organic grain. I've got all of
these key details that I can then use at
the start of all of my prompts. And I
have this custom baked into every single
prompt that I do with SeaDance. It gives
me the same high-quality results every
single time. So you can also see that
we've got it broken down into the cast.
So SeaDance knows who the cast is. And
then when you paste your prompt into any
kind of platform that you want to create
with SeaDance, you can actually tag
those characters in that area. So let me
show you. So if we were to do SeaDance
2.5 here for example, in the prompt we
can go ahead and remove that in here. We
can paste this prompt in. Now you can
see if we scroll down in here where we
get to the characters, you can see here
it says "Rogue, mid-30s, shoulder-length
hair." So we can now go ahead and start
uploading our elements in here. So we
can upload our files and upload all of
our character sheets in here. Now while
these are uploading, I'm going to show
you why this is important because if you
use, for example, SeaDance on other
platforms like Dreena, you only get
5,000 characters that you can use.
Whereas on Higgsfield, you can actually
use a lot more characters. Why is this
important? Because it allows you to get
super descriptive and detailed with your
prompts. So you can get all the custom
acting performances that you want, so
all the nuances, all the imperfections,
you can get all of those with SeaDance.
Because if you're trying to do a
30-second long generation, you need as
many characters as you can get to be as
detailed as you possibly can be. Now
here, check this out. So, if I click on
this, we can upload that as a reference
in here. We can upload my friend as a
reference in here. And we can then go in
and tag them. So, for example, Rogue, we
can go in and tag so we can give that a
reference. My mate in here, we can go in
and tag and give that a reference. And
you can do that so forth with all of
your prompts. So, you can go in and you
can detail out the the lady as well. You
can also detail the location and tag
that as a as a reference as well. Um and
you can see by giving Claude context of
the characters and also the location, it
can use those descriptive terms inside
of the scenes. It's really really
important that you give these as
references to Claude to give you the
best results. Now you can see in here,
it's going to detail out the style of
shot. Is it a close-up? Is it a medium
shot? Where is the camera positioned?
Behind them? Is it a reveal? Okay, so we
have all of these like nice camera
terminology. You can also see we've got
everything broken down into time codes.
So, we know exactly how long each shot
is going to be on scene for. So, you can
also see in the prompt in here, we've
still got that key terminology,
"obnoxious half laugh for a second, then
flat and certain." So,
uh you know, we've got the detail of how
we want the acting nuances to go ahead.
So, what we can do is just copy this, go
straight into SeaDance, and then we can
go ahead and start generating. So, down
here you can see that you can adjust the
duration of your video all the way to 30
seconds. You can adjust the aspect
ratio. I like to do 16 by 9. And you can
see here the quality we have, maximum is
720p. Now you can also switch on
unlimited mode if you purchase that
plan, and then you can start generating.
Now, while that's loading, I'm going to
show you something else which is super
cool. So, what you can do with Seed Ar
2.5 is you can create 3D movement,
right, with custom tools like Blender,
for example, where we create the camera
motion and we dictate exactly the style
of the shot that we want, and you can
upload that as a reference. And Seed Ar
2.0 can actually adhere to that really,
really well. And you can upload your own
reference image of the location, for
example. You can also upload a character
sheet of, you know, who you want to
transfer onto that mannequin, and you
can then create shots like this. I mean,
just look how impressive this is. This
is super, super impressive, and you have
so much control now with this model. So,
you can really lock in this exact camera
motion you want. You can lock in the
exact movement you want, all in 3D in
pre-production, you know, so that you
can then see maybe how it's going to
look on set in the real thing. So, the
whole pre-production process can really,
really be nailed down with this new
tool. So, while that generation's
loading, I just want to walk you through
my actual editing timeline. So, you can
see in here, we've got our, you know,
core videos in here, and we've got our
sound underneath, and you can see that
we really don't have too many layers
here. The color grading is great out of
the model, so we don't really need to do
any tweaks, but you can also add your
own Lumetri color effects on it if you
wanted to to adjust the color grading.
But, let's take a look, right? So, if I
just mute all of this audio, so we can
just have a little look-see together.
You can see in here, um I've just added
my own subtitles at the bottom, and
we've kind of edited the 30-second
generation down a little bit to cut out
any of those like awkward silences, so
that we can really lock in all of the
right timing that we want. Cuz a lot of
the time, when you do the generation,
there might be like an extra awkward
second of silence that you might just
want to cut out. So, we'll go in and
make those tweaks manually, but what I
really like doing is running three
generations of 30 seconds and then
mining out the best parts of each of
those and taking the best parts of each
and then clipping that all together
until you have a really nice 30 second
sequence. So, not all of the time you're
going to get perfection straight out the
model. Obviously, if you're really
really talented, you might get super
lucky on your first go, but that's a bit
of gambling. So, what we like to do is
do one generation, test to see how it
how it looks, how is the acting
performance looking? Are we getting the
results that we want? And then if it's
not there, then we go back, we refine
the prompt with Claude. We say, "Okay,
this is cool. This is, you know, the
acting performance here is good. Maybe
here it's not so good. Let's change
this. Let's change that." And we'll
refine. Then you go back, you paste that
prompt in and then you redo it again.
You see the acting performance. Is it
good? Yes, I'm happy. Okay, now we're
going to use this three times. We're
going to take the best parts of each of
the prompts and we're going to put that
together to build something beautiful.
So, that's really like how we like to
work. So, you might take like the best
parts of of each part and kind of stitch
it all together. It's probably important
to mention as well, the only real
editing that we actually did in here was
adding in our own music track to this
scene right here to really emphasize all
of the hat like a comedic value. So,
that's really one of the only editing
parts that we did in this video. So,
here is our generation right here.
Do you mind doing my back?
[\h__\h] off. I'm not doing that, mate. Come
on. It'll only take
>> Go on then. Can you do both of us?
Protects your skin, not your dignity.
>> Now, it's not bad to begin with. Now,
what you can do is go back with Claude
or refine and constantly edit until you
get the exact results you want. And you
can just talk with the AI and just say,
"I want to change this. I want to change
this." And you can keep massaging it
until you get an output that you're
happy with. But, make sure once you've
got to a position that you're happy, you
then run three generations and take the
best parts from each one, stitch it
together. You still got to do a little
bit of manual tweaking in there to
elevate it. Now, to make it even better,
I would say you want to add in your own
subtle color grading with Lumetri color
effects, maybe a bit of film grain in
there as well, to really take it to that
next level. So, it doesn't feel like
something that's super polished that's
come straight out of an AI video model.
So, honestly, creating really
high-quality work has never been easier.
And right now, behind the scenes, we're
actually working on one of the most
incredible automations that can automate
the entire process of creating cinematic
ads, which sounds ridiculous to say, but
we're going to be releasing something on
that in the next week. So, make sure you
stick around for that one. Also, if
you're interested in learning more about
creative AI and actually turning it into
your full-time career, then you can come
and join Gen HQ. We've generated over a
million dollars for our students so far,
and I'm hoping that you can be the next
one to find a full-time job or even
start getting paid by your first AI
client. And we teach you all of those
skills in Gen HQ, not just the tools,
but actually how to build a career in
this space. So, if you're interested,
there's a link in the description as
well. You can come and join us over
there. We're one of the most successful
communities in the world for creative
AI. And that's everything you need to
know about Seedorn's 2.5. So, if you
want to try out unlimited for the next
33 days, you can click the first link in
the description. And if you're
interested in learning more about
creative AI and turning it into your
full-time career, then you can check out
Gen HQ. Thank you very much for
watching, guys, and I'll see you in the
[music] next one.